# Golder Otobotekere

in linkedin.com/in/golder-otobotekere-090b77147/ https://github.com/GoldingGees

### **Professional Summary:**

Over 10 years experience in personnel and office administration. Invaluable two years experience in workforce planning and coordination in one of the leading oil and gas industries. Excellent teamwork spirit, to proffer solutions that meet business needs and organizational goals. Self-starter, dedicated, detailed and committed to target objectives. Good humor and easy to be around. Fast visual learner, self-motivated, flexible and driven by new challenges and good working conditions.

## Educational Background:

**2022** Generations USA - Junior Web Development (W3Schools Javascript Certificate *in progress; expected date of completion* **12/2022**)

**2013** Chartered Institute of Personnel Management Nigeria – Prof. Diploma in Human Resources Mgt.

**2006** Nigerian Institute of Management (NYSC-Kaduna) – Proficiency Certificate in Management.

**2004** University of Port Harcourt – Foreign Languages & Literatures (French major) –B.A, CGPA – 4.47

## **Career History**

**Nov 2017 – Apr 2020:** 

Workforce Coordinator, Schlumberger - Well Services (Nig, Ghana, IVC, Mauritania)

- Plan and coordinate personnel mobilization and demobilization to/from rig and land locations
- Monitor personnel competencies, future training requirements and client certifications
- Manage contractor and employee payroll, days off and vacation balances
- Monitor headcount
- Coordinate logistics within company HSE standards
- Work with LM to close gaps and address personnel needs

#### Mar 2010 – Oct 2017:

**Segment/ Business Systems Administrator** (Schlumberger Nigeria Limited - Well Services)

- Track personnel activities for payroll inputs
- Plan all office events including meetings, trainings and get-togethers
- Oversee all office administrative works
- Update system with client contract for field ticketing
- Use field business systems to monitor and support operations in planning and execution of jobs

## Chemical inventory management analyst and coordinator responsibilities:

- Collate and analyze quarterly inventory forecasts
- Place and follow up chemical orders dispatched from the hub
- Manage inventory to prevent shortages and excesses
- Monitor delivery from port to warehouse and provide feedback to requestors

#### Jul '07 – Feb 2010:

### HR Transactions Assistant (Personnel Center) – Schlumberger Support Nigeria Limited

- Onboarding process for new employees, interns and transferred-in
- Manage employee documents and files
- Initiate probation and confirmation of employment of new hires
- Respond to employee queries and requests
- Process monthly payroll
- Track vacation reports and update on the personnel server monthly
- Review and process IS expense claims
- Provide support to Line Managers and Personnel Managers
- Personnel benefits administration: housing, furniture, mobility and training/travel advances/allowances, loans, etc.

2005-2006: NYSC – English Instructor - School of Administration (SOA) & Regiment

Training School (RTS) 325 Ground Training Group (GTG), Nigerian Air Force Base,

Kaduna. (NYSC)

## Leadership roles:

2017 - 2019

- Team Leader, Well Services LPT (Loss Prevention Team)
- Plan and Participate in safety meetings, yard inspections and audits
- Initiate projects to improve HSE in the workplace
- Implement management decisions or changes to safety
- Reduce losses or hazards in the work environment and to improve processes

## Skills:

- Reliable
- Self-motivated
- Dedicated
- Team player and leader
- Problem solving skills
- Detail orientation
- Communication and organizing skills
- Follow up shampion
- Fast learner and good teacher
- Microsoft office proficiency
- Javascript
- Html
- CSS
- Git & GitHub
- Bootstrap
- French

## **Hobbies & Interests:**

Reading | Singing | Writing | Traveling | Speaking | Sewing Youth advisor/counselor | Woodworks | Home decor.

**Referee:** available upon request.